<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2026 Gabriel Maizo González <maizogabriel@gmail.com>
SPDX-License-Identifier: CC0-1.0
-->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.kde.kio-rclone-config</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0-or-later</project_license>
  <developer id="io.github.undead34">
    <name>Gabriel Maizo</name>
  </developer>
  <name>Rclone Remotes</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Remotos Rclone</name>
  <summary>Configure cloud storage for Dolphin</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Configura almacenamiento en la nube para Dolphin</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      KIO Rclone browses the remotes already configured in rclone from Dolphin
      and every other KIO-aware application, exposing them as a normal-looking
      rclone:/ location. It deliberately does not depend on KDE Online
      Accounts or LibKGAPI: rclone owns OAuth, provider APIs, retries and the
      user's credentials.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="es">
      KIO Rclone permite navegar, desde Dolphin y cualquier otra aplicación
      compatible con KIO, los remotos ya configurados en rclone, exponiéndolos
      como una ubicación rclone:/ normal. Deliberadamente no depende de
      Cuentas en línea de KDE ni de LibKGAPI: rclone es quien maneja OAuth,
      las APIs de cada proveedor, los reintentos y las credenciales del
      usuario.
    </p>
    <p>
      This configuration utility manages rclone remotes: add Google Drive,
      reconnect an expired session, or set up a private Google OAuth client to
      avoid rclone's shared, quota-limited client. Credentials and OAuth
      tokens are always stored by rclone itself and are never copied into KIO
      Rclone.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="es">
      Esta utilidad de configuración administra remotos de rclone: agregar
      Google Drive, reconectar una sesión vencida, o configurar un cliente
      OAuth de Google privado para evitar el cliente compartido y limitado en
      cuota de rclone. Las credenciales y los tokens OAuth siempre quedan
      guardados por rclone mismo, nunca se copian a KIO Rclone.
    </p>
    <p>Supported operations once a remote is configured:</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Operaciones disponibles una vez configurado un remoto:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Browse remotes and folders</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Navegar remotos y carpetas</li>
      <li>Download and upload through Dolphin, with live progress</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Descargar y subir archivos desde Dolphin, con progreso en vivo</li>
      <li>Create, rename and delete files and directories</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Crear, renombrar y eliminar archivos y carpetas</li>
      <li>Open and edit ordinary documents through KIOFuse</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Abrir y editar documentos comunes a través de KIOFuse</li>
      <li>Pause and cancel transfers through normal KIO backpressure</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Pausar y cancelar transferencias con la contrapresión normal de KIO</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.kde.kio-rclone-config.desktop</launchable>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/Undead34/kio-rclone</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/Undead34/kio-rclone/issues</url>
  <url type="help">https://undead34.github.io/kio-rclone/</url>
  <categories>
    <category>Network</category>
    <category>FileTransfer</category>
    <category>Qt</category>
    <category>KDE</category>
  </categories>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>rclone</keyword>
    <keyword>cloud</keyword>
    <keyword>cloud storage</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="es">nube</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="es">almacenamiento en la nube</keyword>
    <keyword>dolphin</keyword>
    <keyword>google drive</keyword>
    <keyword>s3</keyword>
    <keyword>dropbox</keyword>
    <keyword>onedrive</keyword>
    <keyword>remote</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="es">remoto</keyword>
    <keyword>kio</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <icon type="stock">org.kde.kio-rclone-config</icon>
  <provides>
    <binary>kio-rclone-config</binary>
  </provides>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.4.2" date="2026-07-20">
      <description>
        <p>
          Remotes in rclone:/ now show a themed icon for Google Drive,
          Dropbox and OneDrive instead of a generic folder. The configuration
          window's description and empty-state hint were reworded.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.1" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>
          The "Configure Remotes…" entry is now a shortcut to the installed
          launcher instead of a folder the file worker opened by launching the
          application itself. Listing rclone:/ no longer starts any window, so
          recursive scans cannot trigger it, and a single window is guaranteed
          by the application's own single-instance registration.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.0" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>
          Adds OneDrive and Dropbox to the guided Add Remote flow, an Edit
          dialog for renaming remotes and changing their OAuth client, support
          for encrypted rclone configurations, and a Spanish translation of the
          whole interface.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.1" date="2026-07-17">
      <description>
        <p>
          Fixes the configuration window opening unbounded duplicate copies of
          itself when its KIO entry is listed repeatedly. It now enforces a
          single running instance and raises the existing window instead.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.0" date="2026-07-16">
      <description>
        <p>
          Fixes safe, atomic remote file transfers: uploads publish only after
          the full transfer succeeds, duplicate remote names resolve to one
          deterministic entry, and Google-native document exports report their
          real size before opening.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.0" date="2026-07-10">
      <description>
        <p>
          Adds live rclone upload progress, streams only the requested remote
          file during downloads, and adds private Google OAuth client
          configuration.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
